Goh Chun Shan

Mobile: +65 97109881 | Email: gohchunshan@gmail.com | Nationality: Singaporean | github: gohchunshan

Career Objective

As a civil servant with more than 4 years of experience, my interest in Data science was piqued when I saw how data was used to support critical operations in a health crisis during the Covid-19 pandemic, which led me to expose myself to data science training and healthcare research projects in my free time. I am confident in my logical thinking and problem-solving skills, and am always thinking of "why" and "how" things are done. Where possible, I attempt to make processes at work more efficient by minimizing repetitive tasks through automation and systemisation. I hope to further my career by contributing towards data science analytics, particularly in the field of MedTech.

Work Experience

Manager, Public Health and Surveillance, ACE Group

Oct 2020 - current

Ministry of Manpower

- Contributed to the fight against Covid-19 as part of the Joint Task Force (Assurance) which oversaw the nation-wide operations for containing disease spread in migrant worker dormitories from Apr to Sep 2020
- Set up a Public Health surveillance system from scratch for migrant workers using a web application within 3 months of ideation, by collaborating with clinicians and multiple teams from Ministry of Health (MOH), Integrated Health Information Systems (IHIS) and Clinic Management Systems (CMS)
- Monitored the key performance indexes (KPIs) for daily reporting of Covid-19 situation in dormitories, for Acute Respiratory Infection (ARI) and other infectious disease surveillance, and indicators for performance of the medical centres for migrant workers
- Co-ordinated high-level discussions between public sector ministries regarding system ownership, funding and future plans of the flagship MWHealth surveillance system
- Analysed and presented cohort studies to public service senior management on various topics such as vaccination effectiveness, Long Covid and underlying causes of death among dormitory migrant workers

Statistical Specialist, Data Collection, Manpower Research and Statistics Department Jul 2018 – Sep 2020 Ministry of Manpower

- Designed questionnaires for regular and ad-hoc surveys targeted at establishments' Human Resource Department
- Created and implemented validation rules in a survey system
- Conducted regular survey concept training sessions for office interviewers and team leads
- Coordinated stakeholder input from various departments to deliberate the data needs of the Ministry for inclusion in surveys
- Gathered feedback directly from respondents and proposed solutions to customise and improve the data collection process

MOE Teaching Intern

Jan 2014 - Mar 2014

MacPherson Secondary School

- Taught Mathematics and Pure Physics to Secondary 2, 3 and 5 students
- Evaluated teaching materials and classroom styles in department meetings, and recommended use of learning aides such as videos to enhance learning and capture attention of students

Education

General Assembly Data Science Immersive Flex (Batch 7)

Aug 2022 - Mar 2023

• Data Science Immersive Flex-7 Capstone Project: Chinese Calligraphy

Nanyang Technological University (NTU)

Aug 2014 - May 2018

- BSc. Mathematics and Economics (Honours)
- CN Yang Scholars' Programme/ Nanyang Scholarship recipient
- Spring Exchange Programme at Fudan University, Shanghai, China

Hwa Chong Institution (College)

Jan 2012 -

Dec 2013

• GCE 'A' Levels, Integrated Programme

Skills, Projects and Publications

- Proficient in Python (numpy, pandas), R (Desktop), STATA, Data Visualisation (PowerBI, Tableau)
- Languages: Proficient in English, Chinese, Basic German
- Association of Cardiovascular Lipid Profile with Osteoporosis: A Systematic Review Protocol (in review)

Professional Certification and Awards

- Professional Certificate in Outbreak Alert and Response (S-FETP Tier 2)
- Commendation Medal (Covid-19)